onnanoko hajimemashita
A tired girl starts her day
tameiki wa bioron no shirabe ni nite
With a sigh like the moan of a violin
akai mi hajikechatta
A cherry bursts in her mouth
mada anata wo shiranai
This was before we had met
konna koto hajimetette
This is the first time I've ever felt like this
manazashi wa aku no hana sakimidarete mo
I could see that your pretty eyes were filled with contempt
ie e to tsuzuku
But I had to go home
basu sutoppu demo anata wa tsurenai
Even at the bus stop, you gave me the cold shoulder
karameta hanabi myaku utsu
The fireworks in the sky pulse
koi no shiruetto
In a silhouette of love
karui mahou
With a little magic,
usotsuki na kuchibiru
Two sets of lying lips
sou kasaneteru
Lock together
ano ne
You see
nee kamisama
God...
warui ko ni naritai yo
I'd like to be a naughty girl
ii ko ni shiteru kara
I'm tired of being good
onegai dayo
So, please
zurui koto sasetoite
It's for a good reason
ii koto shitai nara
So let me be bad for once
sukaato hirogaesu shite
By flipping my skirt
sugu kaeru yo
I'll be back soon
doyoubi wa haresou da
It looks like Saturday is going to be sunny
kamisama hajimemashita
God, it has already started
Using the time-wending incense burner to travel back in time,
（講釈師）
時廻(ときまわ)りの香炉で―
過去へ飛んだ奈々生(ななみ)は―
今 まさに 龍王から
右目を奪ってきた巴衛(ともえ)と遭遇
Nanami encounters Tomoe who had just then stolen the Dragon King's right eye.
Now he stands before her, although she hardly recognizes this wild fox.
目の前にいるのは
まだ 奈々生の知らない野狐(やこ)の巴衛
The God Goes To The Dragon King's Palace
（奈々生）
あれが 龍王の目
That's the Dragon King's eye.
Wait! Come back!
あっ 待って！
（奈々生）
巴衛！
Tomoe!
Tomoe's getting away.
巴衛が行っちゃう
わあっ！
There's no way you can catch up on foot.
（瑞希(みずき)）
走って追いつくわけ
ないでしょう？
Are you really a land god, Nanami?
奈々生ちゃんって
本当に土地神様？
（奈々生）
すみません
Sorry.
That's right.
そうだよね
There's no way the Tomoe of this time period would recognize me.
この時代の巴衛が 私のこと
知ってるはずないんだった
So do you have any idea where he's going?
巴衛 どこに行く気なのかな
Hm... Perhaps he has a party at his hideout,
（瑞希）
うーん　龍王の目を さかなに
アジトで宴会ってとこじゃない？
and he's bringing the Dragon King's eye as a side dish.
We have to get the Dragon King's eye back!
龍王の目 取り返さなきゃ
If we can somehow explain the situation to Tomoe...
何とか巴衛に事情を説明すれば…
Silly girl.
（瑞希）
ばかだな
そんなの 聞くわけないじゃないか
He won't listen to any explanation.
隙を見て盗むしかないよ　君がね
The only option now is to steal it.
Can you handle it?
Really?
盗む
あの家…
That house?
Looks like it.
（瑞希）
だね
（雪路(ゆきじ)）
潮の香りがする
I can smell the salt on you.
You went all the way to the sea to buy medicine?
海まで
薬を買いに行っていたのか？
Yes.
（巴衛）
ああ
おかげで 良い薬が手に入った
What I have found was worth the risk.
All you have to do is take this, and your illness will be cured.
（巴衛）
これを飲めば
お前の病も きっと良くなる
Yukiji.
雪路
Get well...
ずっと 俺と生きよう
Live eternally with me...
（奈々生）
同じ顔 同じ声なのに―
That's his face.
And his voice.
Yet I can hardly recognize him.
こんな巴衛 私は知らない
He did it for her.
全ては―
He stole the eye and put his life at risk for her.
あの人のために支払った
代償だったんだ
She's so beautiful.
きれいな人
（瑞希）
奈々生ちゃんは 誰かを
妬ましく思ったことはない？
Is this the first time you've felt the pain of jealousy and envy?
You understand me now.
僕と同じように
It is too large to swallow like this.
これでは飲みにくかろう
Such fine medicine is rare.
せっかくの良い薬だ
I will fetch you fresh spring water to go with it.
これに見合う清水を
くんできてやる　しばし待て
I shall return.
Nanami, you're going to get the Dragon King's eye back, right?
奈々生ちゃん
龍王の目を 取り返すんでしょ？
（雪路）
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
That's right, Nanami.
（瑞希）
そうだよ 奈々生ちゃん
僕だったら しくじったりしない
If it were up to me, the task would be completed.
だって その女は目障りだもの
That woman is in your way.
Hang in there!
しっかり！
これを飲めば大丈夫だから！
You'll be fine once you take this!
Here.
さあ
What are you doing, Nanami?!
何してんの 奈々生ちゃん
瑞希
Mizuki!
You came here to retrieve the Dragon King's eye.
龍王の目 取り返しに来たのに
あげてどうするの！
Why would you give it away?!
（奈々生）
だって…
But...
その娘を助けて
後悔することになってもいいの？
Do you realize what you could be risking if you chose her life over another?
Sure, I...
私だって 巴衛のこと助けたい
want to save Tomoe.
But...
でも 目の前で苦しんでる人を―
someone's suffering right in front of me.
見殺しにはできないよ
I can't stand by and do nothing!
That's why...
だから…
Thank you, Mizuki.
ありがとう 瑞希
But why?
（瑞希）
どうして…
Yukiji.
（奈々生）
雪路さん
Thank goodness.
よかった
治まったみたいね
It looks like she's better.
行こう 奈々生ちゃん
Let's go, Nanami.
Wending through time as your
corporeal self doesn't last long.
実体での時廻りは 長くはもたない
Your time is up.
時間切れだ
The solution was never going to be found in the past.
（奈々生）
過去に付けを払わせちゃ駄目だ
今の付けは 今で払わなきゃ
What I owe now, I have to pay in the present.
巴衛
Tomoe...
（瑞希）
おかえり
Welcome back.
瑞希！
Mizuki!
Krik
You'd better not move too suddenly.
急に動かないほうがいいよ
体 痛いでしょ？
I bet your body aches.
That's the price of wending through time in person.
生身で時廻りした代償ってやつ
So what do you plan to do now?
それで これから どうする気？
I saw Isohime in the past.
過去で会った磯姫(いそひめ)に―
Is there any way I could find her again in the present?
この時代で
もう一度 会えないかな
Isohime?
磯姫に？
会って どうするのさ
Why do you want to see her?
She said something I want to ask about.
（奈々生）
彼女 確かに こう言ったの
The Dragon King's eye inside of you...
（磯姫）
お前の中にある その龍王の目
私にくれたら あげてもいいよ
Give it to me, and in return, I'll give you this cloak.
She told me that the Dragon King's eye was inside me.
私の中に 龍王の目があるって
Then she asked if I wanted to trade it for her cloak.
それを 着物と交換しないかって
That might be...
それが―
the key to saving Tomoe.
巴衛を救える鍵になるかも
Hey, lady, you run a shop in this cave here?
姉ちゃん
こんな洞窟で 店 開いてんのか？
Late at night, only for a limited time.
（磯姫）
深夜 限定でね
Feed this fruit to any woman,
and she'll do whatever you want.
この実を食わせれば
どんな女も意のままだよ
Let me think...
そうだね
あんたの着けてる金の指輪となら
交換して…
Perhaps I'll trade it for the gold ring you're wearing. Good deal, right?
Wh-What the?! Is it high tide?!
な… 何だ 満潮か？
Crap! Let's go back!
やっべえ 戻ろうぜ
あっ ちょっと！
I'm not done with you!
You haven't changed a bit in 500 years.
500年前と変わらないね
But thanks to that, you were easy to find.
おかげで 捜すの楽だったけど
Who the hell are you guys?!
（磯姫）
何だ あんたたち！
Isohime, I want to make a deal with you.
磯姫 取り引きしたいの
So on
and so
forth
Uh-huh
So on
and so
forth
Uh-huh
So on
and so
forth
Uh-huh
So on
What did you say?!
何だって？
You're going to give me the Dragon King's eye?!
龍王の目を 私にくれるって？
Where?! Where?! Where do you have it?!
どこ？　どこにあんの？
な… 何か この人
500年前とテンションが違う
I have to say, you were a lot different 500 years ago!
That's not what I meant!
そうじゃなくて！
You told me the Dragon King's eye was inside of me.
私の中に龍王の目があるのなら
それを取り出してほしいの
I need you to help me get it out.
Let's have a look.
どれ　なるほど
I see.
It's awfully worn down and tiny, but I can definitely see something that looks like it inside your body.
確かに
随分 削れて小さいけど―
それらしき物は 体内に見えるわね
Really?
本当に？
Don't let this bod fool you. I know what I'm doing.
こう見えて 私の目は確かなの
All right.
いいよ
代わりに あんたの何をくれる？
What are you going to give me in exchange?
Anything! As long as it's in my power to give you.
（奈々生）
何でも！
私に あげられるものなら
Really?
（磯姫）
そう？
Well, then...
じゃあ
あんたの寿命 30年分でどうだ！
How about thirty years of your life?!
That's the best deal I've got!
出血大サービスだよ！
（瑞希）
アハハッ
30年とは 随分 吹っかけるね
Thirty years? Talk about a rip-off.
She knows you're desperate, so she's
taking advantage of you. Don't trust her.
そんなやつ 信用することないよ
奈々生ちゃん
Then do you know how to get it?
じゃあ お前に取れんのかい？
玉の場所も分からないくせに
You don't even know where the eye is!
Both my eyes have second sight.
私の両目は千里眼
見えない物なんかないんだよ
There's nothing I can't see through.
Keep out of this, you pathetic snake boy has-been.
神使崩れの蛇坊やは 引っ込んでな
Fine. Let's make the deal for thirty years of my life.
いいわ 30年分の寿命で
取り引きしましょう
What?!
うーん 話が分かるじゃないの
Hm, there's a girl who knows how to bargain.
Nanami!
（瑞希）
奈々生ちゃん！
Don't do this.
やめなよ
It'll be okay.
大丈夫 若いんだから
I'm still young, you know.
Not like I'm gonna die if she takes thirty years.
30年くらい持っていかれたって
私 死んだりしないよ
でも
巴衛には もう１日しかないから
It's Tomoe who might only have one more day to live.
You're so stupid.
（瑞希）
ばかだよ
You're barely capable of doing anything,
何にもできないくせに
どうして そっちに行っちゃうかな
so why are you taking these risks?
You always get in over your head.
手に負えないことばっかり
引き受けて
I can't put up with it anymore.
もう つきあいきれないや
（磯姫）
さあ 横になんな
Go on, lie down.
さてと
寿命は後払いにしてあげるよ
Now then, I'll let you pay me the years of your life upon delivery.
Relax.
力を抜いて　すぐ終わるから
This'll be over in no time.
フフッ 私の両目は千里眼
Why thank you, second sight.
寿命なんかより もっといい物を
お前が持ってることなんか―
My, my. It appears you have something much
more valuable than years, little miss land god.
お見通しだよ
土地神の お嬢ちゃん
アーッハッハッハッ…
The land god's soul and the Dragon King's eye!
土地神の み霊と龍王の目
磯姫 頂戴！
They're mine now!
See? I tried to warn you.
（瑞希）
ほらね だから言ったのにさ
Would it have been so difficult for you to listen and trust me to protect you?
僕の言うこと聞いてれば
よかったでしょ 奈々生ちゃん
Tomoe only has himself to blame for what happened.
巴衛君は 自業自得
It is not your responsibility to take on his debt.
君が 肩代わりする必要なんか
なかったのに
本当に 奈々生ちゃんは
僕なんかじゃ及びもつかない
Your kindness is relentless.
Nothing I said was going to stop you.
You don't even have a familiar at your side right now.
手足になる神使もいず―
Since your mortal soul is what leads you to protect others,
人の身で
誰かを守ろうというのなら―
your heart is what leads me to serve you.
もう一度 お仕えしよう
これが僕の 最上級の敬意
This is my way...
of showing how much I truly respect you.
The cage around my heart is breaking away.
心の澱(おり)が消えていく
You... Why?
お前 どうして
I will continue to stay by her side.
（瑞希）
彼女のそばにいれば…
I'll be able to be myself again.
僕は もう一度 僕になれる
right up
Next part coming
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
（奈々生）うーん
（瑞希）僕の新しい ご主人様
My new lady and mistress.
Did you sleep well?
お目覚めは いかが？
What?
Today is the day I, Mizuki,
serve you as your new familiar.
今日から この瑞希は
奈々生ちゃんの神使になりました
I'll be so useful that I'll blow
Tomoe clear out of the water!
巴衛君なんか吹き飛ばすくらい
役に立っちゃうよ
Huh? What? Wait a second. What are you talking about?
うん？　何… 待って待って
どういうこと？
Well, you see, I...
（瑞希）
だから 僕がね
磯姫　僕の主人に
手を出したからにはさ―
Isohime, since you tried to hurt
and deceive my lady and mistress,
it wouldn't be right to let you get away with that, would it?
このままで済むと
思ってないよね？
Mizuki!
瑞希！　殺しちゃ駄目！
Don't kill her!
Sacred Word Binding ensures absolute obedience.
（瑞希）
言霊縛りは 絶対服従の印
Sweet paralysis...
甘い しびれ
神に支配されているという快感
The pleasure of being held under a god's control...
It's euphoric! Please give me more commands!
たまらない
もっと言って 奈々生ちゃん
Tie me up with your invisible chain of words!
その見えない鎖で 僕を縛って！
ひどいわ 瑞希
You're disgusting!
In other words, you kissed me
without asking me while I slept?!
つまり 私が寝ている間に
勝手にキスしたってこと？
You pervert! That's sexual assault!
痴漢　強制わいせつ！
何か ずれてるけど―
That assessment is a little over the top,
but I'm glad you understand the situation.
状況は分かってるみたいで
よかったよ
This is the Dragon King's eye?
（奈々生）
これが 龍王の目？
It's barely the size of a pinball.
こんなパチンコ玉みたいなのが…
Who cares what size it is? It's still the Dragon King's eye, isn't it?
形はどうあれ
龍王の目には違いないし―
Let's hurry and get it back to him.
さっさと龍王に返しちゃおうよ
にしても 磯姫のやつ…
But about Isohime...
Turtle Taxi
Land
Dragon King's
Palace
One ticket per person, good for one use.
I didn't take anything, so take these, and we'll call it even!
何も 取らなかったんだから
これで チャラにしてよね！
Flee
She said they're tickets to go to the Dragon King's Palace.
竜宮行きの乗車券だってさ
I still don't think you should've let her off the hook so easily.
こんなので許しちゃうなんて
甘いよ 奈々生ちゃん
I'm just relieved that you didn't do anything to her.
私は 瑞希が何もしなくて
ほっとしてるよ
I assure you a familiar will never kill in front of his god.
神使は
主人の前で殺生なんかしないよ
巴衛君も きっと同じ
Surely Tomoe was the same, right?
奈々生ちゃんの前では
手を汚したくないのさ
He never wanted you to see his
dirty work. It might've upset you.
（魚人１）
龍王様！
Lord Dragon King!
（魚人２）
大変でございます！
There's trouble!
（龍王）
うるせえぞ！
計算中は静かにしろ！
Shut up! Can't you see I'm calculating?!
It's the White-Lipped Oyster that was set up in the banquet hall!
（魚人１）
宴会場に設置した白蝶貝(しろちょうがい)が！
Tomoe?
（龍王）
巴衛が？
（巴衛）
やれやれ　肉に包まれる感触が
懐かしくて―
Good grief.
The sensation of being wrapped in flesh brought back such fond memories. I dozed off in spite of myself.
つい まどろんでしまった
It's been a long time, Dragon King, has it not?
久しぶりだったな 龍王
You had some nerve showing your face right in front of Nanami.
奈々生の目の前で
よくも顔を出してくれたものだ
Smart move as you know I will not conduct bloody business in front of my mistress.
主人の前で
血生臭いことはできんのでな
Which is why I decided to change venues.
（巴衛）
場所を改めさせてもらったぞ
（奈々生）
わあ すごい
Wow, this is incredible!
竜宮城って
本当に亀に乗って行くのね
You really do have to ride a turtle
to get to the Dragon King's Palace.
Nanami, that window will let everything through except water, so you need to be careful.
奈々生ちゃん そのガラス―
水以外は通り抜けちゃうから
気を付けてって…
Now I can rescue Tomoe.
（奈々生）
これで 巴衛を助けられる
巴衛に会える　今の巴衛に やっと
I'll get to see him again.
The Tomoe of the present.
Finally!
Huh?
あれ？　何だろう 私…
What's gotten into me?
瑞希
Mizuki.
うん？　何…
What is it?
巴衛は 雪路さんのこと―
Do you think Tomoe...
まだ好きなのかな
still has feelings for Yukiji?
私 会うのが少し怖いんだ
I'm...
a little scared of seeing him.
きっと比べちゃう
All I can think about is her.
あの人には
もっと優しかったのに…
He was kinder to her.
His feelings were passionate.
あの人には
もっと必死だったのに…
私には…
But...
he won't even touch me.
触れてもくれない
No! This isn't the time for that!
駄目だ それどころじゃないのに
思考が どんどん後ろ向きに…
My negative thoughts are eating me alive!
Why don't we just forget the trip?
行くの やめちゃう？
Why would I want to do that?
Turtle Taxi Guidebook
何で そうなんのよ
You don't seem enthusiastic about it.
だって 奈々生ちゃん
気が乗らないみたいだから
Turtle Taxi Guidebook
What's wrong, Turtle Taxi?!
どうしたの 亀タク
Turtle Taxi Guidebook
We have a customer getting on at an unscheduled stop.
（亀タク）
途中乗車の お客様です
Pardon me for sharing your ride.
（亀姫(かめひめ)）
同乗 失礼します
One of the dragon folk?
（奈々生）
龍族の人？
Hello.
こんにちは
P-Please, the pleasure is ours. Nice to meet you.
こ… こちらこそ よろしくです
Not good!
いかん 自分以外の女性が
全員 美の女神に見える
Why am I the only woman I know who doesn't look like a goddess?
What business does a god of the land have at the Dragon King's Palace?
（亀姫）
陸の神が
竜宮に 何の御用向きなのですか？
Oh, uh... A lot of things happened and...
えっと いろいろあって―
Someone I care about is being held
as collateral, so I'm going to get him.
大事な人が 質ぐさになってるんで
迎えに行くんです
My, how terrible for you.
まあ それは大変
I'm sure he's looking forward to seeing you again.
彼も きっと
待っていることでしょう
I understand how you feel. You see, I am on my way to see my beloved husband.
私も いとしい夫に会いに
竜宮に行くところです
I hope we will both see our loved ones soon.
お互い 早く会いたいものですね
Wow, what beautiful embroidery!
わあ きれいな刺しゅう
それ 何ですか
What is that?
（亀姫）
これは あの人に作った羽織です
７日かけて縫いました
This is a half-coat that I made for him.
I spent seven days on the embroidery.
会えない日は そうやって
思いを紡いでいくのです
When I cannot be with my love, that is
how I remind him of my eternal feelings.
What a beautiful gift.
（奈々生）
なんて きれいな着物だろう
I could never make something like that no matter how much time I spent.
私じゃ 10年かかっても
こんなの作れなさそう
（奈々生）
わあーっ！
あっ 羽織が！
The half-coat!
Watch out!
（瑞希）危ない！
（奈々生）瑞希
Mizuki, her half-coat just flew out the window!
奥さんの羽織が
今ので 飛んでいっちゃったの
We have to go look for it!
捜しに行かなきゃ！
いいえ
No.
What?
With that volume of water, it will surely have been carried far away by now.
あの水量では もう遠くまで
流されているでしょう
それよりも 今の水流は
竜宮からの震動ではないかしら
More importantly, I think that stray current may
have been due to a tremor coming from the palace.
I can always make another half-coat.
羽織は また作ればいい
Let us head for the palace right away.
すぐに 竜宮に向かいましょう
But you spent seven days making it.
でも ７日かけて作ったのに…
Yes, I did.
ええ　おかげで この７日間
とても幸せでした
And because of that, those days went by very joyfully.
The memories mean just as much.
今は それで十分
私 恥ずかしいな
I...
feel so ashamed.
さっきまで ずっと―
Until just moments ago, all I'd been thinking about were the things the person I care about wouldn't do for me.
大事な人が 自分にしてくれない
ことばかり考えてました
好いてくれない 触れてくれない
"He won't care for me."
"He won't touch me."
Since when had I become so passive?
いつから 私は こんなに
受け身になってたんだろう
Wow!
わあっ！　こ… ここが竜宮城？
Th-This is the Dragon King's palace?
And...
で…
いつの間にか 瑞希がいないけど
Somewhere along the way, Mizuki's wandered off.
Whoa! What's that?! Construction?!
うわっ！　何… 工事中？
As I feared, something is definitely going on here.
やはり 何か起きているようですね
Lady Kamehime!
（ウミウシたち）
亀姫様！
Sea slugs, what is this commotion about?
（亀姫）
ウミウシ これは何の騒ぎですか？
The fox prisoner suddenly went on a rampage, sea slug.
（ウミウシ１）
捕らえた きつねが
突然 暴れだしてウミウシ
The Lord Dragon King is putting him
down in the western palace, sea slug.
（ウミウシ２）
西の宮で 龍王様が
駆除しておられますウミウシ
（奈々生）
と… 巴衛！
T-Tomoe!
I see.
なるほど
You're much more beastly now
than when I saw you on the beach.
浜で会ったときより
今のほうが ずっと獣らしい
You were right about the way you look.
確かに その姿―
Even a thousand-year love would cool if that girl saw you like that.
あの女が見たら
1,000年の恋も冷めちまうよな
You know Nanami?
奈々生を知っているのか？
お前を返せって
俺に食い下がってきたぜ
She came to pester me and
demanded that I give you back.
俺の目を取り戻して―
She offered to find my right eye
and return it in exchange for you.
お前と交換するとか
言ってたっけな
That is absolute rubbish.
何を ばかなことを
She is the only land god who is incapable of anything.
あいつは 土地神といっても
名ばかりで 何もできん
What?!
えっ？
あの女 土地神だったのか？
That girl's a land god?!
I totally thought she was your lov—
俺は てっきり お前の じょ…
She may not look the part, but she is still the god of Mikage Shrine.
あれでも
れっきとした ミカゲ社の土地神だ
She's not some woman to be touched carelessly with sullied hands.
汚れた手で
気安く触れていい女ではない
Tomoe!
（奈々生）
巴衛！
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
I'm so glad you're okay...
無事でよか…
Clap
What...
どうして閉じ籠もんのよ！
Why would you shut yourself in there?!
It's too late to get in there now!
今更そんなとこ入ったって…
I already know everything!
（たたく音）
（奈々生）全部分かってんだからね
I...
（奈々生）
私 過去に行って
昔の巴衛に会ったよ
went into the past and met the old you.
I don't care if you won't open yourself up to me.
私のこと
受け入れてくれなくてもいいよ
Or if you won't touch me.
触ってくれなくても…
I don't care...
巴衛が 他の人を好きでもいいよ
私は…
even if you have feelings for someone else.
うらーっ！
I'm not going to wait for my
feelings to be returned anymore.
（奈々生）
もう 報われるのを待ったりしない
You're too close...
さ… 触(さわ)…
It doesn't matter that you don't see me that way.
（奈々生）
振り向いてくれなくてもいいよ
Because I'll make you see me that way.
私が 振り向かせるから
Even if you refuse to see as more than a friend...
巴衛が向き合ってくれなくても…
Nothing will change the fact that I have feelings for you.
私が巴衛を好きなことに
変わりない
And that's... enough.
それで十分
Now let's go home.
おうちに帰ろう
I don't get it.
げせん　あの娘が土地神だと？
That girl is a land god?
All I can see is a human girl.
どう見ても 人間の小娘じゃねえか
Um, Lord Dragon King?
（女官）
あの 龍王様…
（亀姫）あなた
（龍王）ぎくっ！
Hello, darling.
Uh...
Do you have explanation for the
unsightly state of the palace, my love?
この竜宮の ありさまは
一体どういうことですの
K-Kamehime, I thought you were visiting your family.
か… 亀姫
実家に帰ってたんじゃ？
うそ　龍王の奥さん？
No way! She's the Dragon King's wife?!
You are still toying with that wild fox in spite of what happened?!
懲りもせずに
また野狐の相手などして
When your eye was stolen, you promised me you would never allow another scar upon your face!
右目を奪われたとき―
今後 一切 顔には傷を作らぬと
約束したのを忘れましたか
Did you forget about that?!
Wait! I can explain!
待て！　これには訳が…
Th-This land god came to return my right eye to me.
こ… この土地神が
俺の右目を返しに来たんだ
Right, land god? Right? Right?
なあ 土地神！　な… なあ？
What? Oh, that's right.
The Dragon King's eye.
龍王の目 お返しします
Here it is.
It's all shriveled up!
干からびてんじゃねえか！
If you would just overlook that...
そこを何とか
The deal's off!
交渉不成立だ！
Okay, then.
（瑞希）
それじゃあさ―
How about we renegotiate for this half-coat?
この羽織で再交渉ってのは どうよ
Mizuki!
（奈々生）
瑞希！
What the hell is that scrap of cloth?
何だ その布きれは
You think you can do business
with me using a piece of trash?!
そんな物(もん)で
俺と取り引きしようってのか
Oh, no. I figured you would want the beautiful gift your wife spent several days making for you.
これは そこの奥方が―
あなたのために
愛情を込めて作った一着
What?
Or is something like this not of equal value to the fox?
それとも―
こんな物では きつねの身柄には
見合いませんか？
You've got a deal!
取り引き成立！
Mizuki!
瑞希！　羽織
拾いに行ってくれてたんだね
So you were out getting the half-coat!
どうして 貴様までここにいる
Please explain to me why you are here.
兄神使の巴衛君が
心配だったからさ
Because I was worried about my big brother familiar.
What?
So there you have it.
というわけで―
これから一緒に
社の仕事しようね 巴衛君
We'll be taking care of the shrine together from now on.
What?!
（巴衛）
何！
I think it's time the three of us...
３人 一緒に おうちに帰ろう
went home.
kamisama onegai da
Please, God
boku no
I...
ano hito ni aitai no sa
I want to meet her
ah ah ah
ah ah ah ah
kamisama tsurain da
God, I'm in pain
kyou mo mata nou ni
Because, she...
konakatta
didn't come today either.
onegai ga aru no kamisama
I have a request, God
boku wo tasukete
Please, save me
ah ah ah ah
kamisama mou osoi
God, it's too late for me
ano ko wa...
Because she's...
Preview
Let's travel back several hundred years ago.
（講釈師）
今より数百年前
Touku sora ni
gone off into the distant sky
This is a story from back when
Tomoe became Mikage's familiar.
巴衛が
ミカゲの神使になったころの お話
Kieta no sa
and disappeared
I wonder what life was like for these two.
この２人の生活って
どんなだったのかしら
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Next time, "Tomoe Becomes A Familiar."
次回「巴衛、神使になる」
Tomoe Becomes A Familiar
What?! There's another story?!
えーっ？　もう１本あるって？
Sayonara baby
Farewell, baby
何？　「神様、合コンにいく」
What's this?! "The God Goes To A Mixer"!
The God Goes To A Mixer
Goodbye, Goodbye
We have a double feature for next time.
次回は 豪華２本立て！